Boys!
Let's do this!
Gray?
Honey, what are you doing?
What is this?
Here. Let's go.
Come on, honey.
Your flight is in two hours.
Dane County Airport is 36 minutes away,
60 with traffic.
How many minutes to get
your little butt in the van?
How many of those?
Feed the monster under your bed?
Yes.
Call me every day,
and text me pics,
so I don't forget what you look like.
I am only gonna be gone a week.
Zach.
You are not going off to war here.
Please.
Come on.
I...
I love you.
Will see you later.
Vámonos.
Bye.
Ok.
Are you in, buddy?
I know it hurts sweetheart.
Are you gonna be ok?
Everything right on there?
I am so jealous.
You are gonna have so much fun.
I love you.
I love you, too.
Ok, great.
Alright.
Give these to your brother, ok?
You hold these, please.
Can you hold these. Honey?
I need you to take care of these.
Yeah.
Hey.
Alright.
Listen to your mother.
Take care of your brother.
Answer your phone.
I am serious.
It's the green button.
When you see my name, push it, ok?
And remember,
something chases you,
run.
Come on.
Yeah.
Alright.
You are funny.
Ok, let's go. Come on.
Bye, guys.
Bye.
I miss you already.
Yeah.
So much for our last family breakfast.
Why do you have
to say things like that?
Did you call your sister?
Straight to voice-mail.
It will be fine.
She handles 20,000 people a day, right?
She can handle two more.
How big is the island?
Big.
But how many pounds?
That doesn't make sense.
When they first opened,
they had eight species.
Now they have 14 herbivores
and six carnivores.
That's 50 tons of food a week.
Welcome to Isla Nublar,
home of Jurassic World.
We hope you have a safe and
enjoyable stay with us.
Where is Aunt Claire?
Ok. Those of you in the front of the train,
Should be able to see our main gates.
Built from the gate of the original park,
over twenty years ago.
Please obey all park rules.
Proper attire, including
shoes and shirts,
must be worn at all times.
Your aunt arranged
to greet you at 1 o'clock.
Can he slow down?
Nope.
Come on!
Your aunt's got you VIP access,
so you can get in all the rides
without waiting in line.
Let's go.
Dude, she said we had to wait.
I don't wanna wait anymore.
Hal Osterly, vice president.
Jim Drucker, bad hair.
Erica Brand, deserves better.
Hal, Jim, Erica.
And I am Claire.
Three minutes late.
Welcome to Jurassic World.
While year over year,
revenue continues to climb,
operating costs are higher than ever.
Our shareholders have been patient,
but, let's be honest.
No one is impressed
by a dinosaur anymore.
Twenty years ago, de-extinction
was right up there with magic.
These days, kids look at a Stegosaurus
like an elephant from the city zoo.
That doesn't mean asset
development is falling behind.
Our DNA excavators,
discover new species every year.
But consumers want them bigger,
louder,
more teeth.
The good news?
Our advances in gene splicing
have opened up a whole new frontier.
We have learned more from
genetics in the past decade
than a century of digging up bones.
So...
when you say you want
to sponsor an attraction,
what do you have in mind?
We want to be thrilled.
Don't we all?
The Indominus Rex.
Our first genetically modified hybrid.
How did you get two different
kinds of dinosaurs to...
you know,
Oh, Indominus was not bred.
She was designed.
She will be 50 feet long
when fully grown.
Bigger than the T-Rex.
Every time we have
unveiled a new asset,
attendance has spiked.
Global news coverage,
celebrity visitors.
Eyes of the world.
When will she be ready?
She already is.
Come on!
Relax.
Come on.
Dude, chill.
Welcome to the Innovation Center,
where technology meets prehistory.
Join us on an exciting journey
65 million years into the past.
The Triceratops can go horn-to-tooth
with the apex predators.
Literally meaning,
three-horned face in Greek,
Triceratops is half as tall as T-Rex
as one-hundred trillion tons of TNT.
Turn its head back
to look over its shoulder
to better aim the swing
of its dangerous tail.
Cytosine, guanine,
adenine and thymine.
The same four things
in everything that ever lived.
Hey, don't wander off alright?
Mom is not paying me for babysitting.
Gray?
Is that you?
Aunt Claire!
Ok, yeah. No, I am gonna have to go.
My nephews are here.
Hi.
Oh, my gosh, you are so...
you are so sweet.
Zach.
Last time I saw you, you were like...
That must have been what?
Three, four years ago?
Seven.
Seven years, but you know, close.
So, I see you already got your wristbands.
And this is for food.
And Zara here is going to take...
great care of you until
I am done working tonight, ok?
You are not coming with us?
Oh, I...
I really wish that I could but I...
tomorrow,
I can take you
into the control room,
show you behind the scenes
and all of that.
That's gonna be cool, right?
Ok, so I...
I will see you tonight at...
6:00.
No, no, no, don't forget you have the...
Right, of course.
I will see you tonight at 8:00.
What time do you go to sleep or...
do you go to sleep at different times?
Ok, so...
have fun,
and take very good care of them, ok?
Yeah. No, I am here.
It's those two juvenile Triceratops.
They are going at it again.
Should I tranq them, or are you
coming over to take care of this?
Go ahead and tranq them.
They are running.
What's the live count?
22,216.
Any incidents?
Yes. Six kids in the Lost and Found.
28 down with heatstroke,
and some...
Where did you get that?
Oh, this?
I got it on eBay.
Yeah, it's pretty amazing.
I got it for $150 but...
the mint condition one goes for $300...
Didn't occur to you maybe
that's in poor taste?
The shirt?
Yeah, no it did.
I understand people died.
It was terrible but...
that first park was a shit.
I have a lot of respect for it.
They didn't need
these genetic hybrids. They...
just needed dinosaurs, real dinosaurs.
Ok, please don't wear it again.
That's kind of enough.
Yeah, I was not gonna.
Did you close the deal?
Looks like it.
Verizon Wireless,
presents the Indominus Rex.
That is so terrible.
Why not just go the distance, Claire,
and just let these corporations
name the dinosaurs?
They have got all the ballparks.
Why stop there?
Why are the West Plains closed?
Another Pachy roaming
outside his zone but...
he is fully sedated
and ready for relocation.
Pepsi-saurus or Tostito-don.
Security said
the invisible fences were a no-fail.
That is the second time this month.
Well, the Pachys short out
their implants when they butt heads.
How much longer
until they get it out of there?
He just got five milligrams of Carfentanil.
Yes, he is very stoned.
So why don't we show a little sympathy?
I mean, you do understand
these are actual animals, right?
Clean up your workspace.
It's...
chaotic.
I like to think of it as a living system.
Just enough stability,
to keep it from collapsing into anarchy.
Inbound chopper Jurassic 1.
ETA, 5 minutes.
Claire.
Mr. Masrani.
You are flying.
I got my license.
Two more.
Well, two more days.
Ok.
So,
how is my park doing?
Great.
We are up 2.5% over last year.
A bit...
lower than our initial projection.
No, no, no, no.
How is it doing?
Are the guests having fun?
Are the animals enjoying life?
Well, guest satisfaction is...
steady in the low 90s.
We don't have a way to measure the...
animals' emotional experience.
Sure you do.
You can see in their eyes.
Right?
Of course.
Ok.
Now show me my new dinosaur.
Got it.
Oh, my!
You look tense, Claire.
Maybe you should just...
focus on the controls.
The key to a happy life is to accept
you are never actually in control.
Bird!
You should spend a day at the beach.
Get some sun.
Right, so...
Marketing...
thought we could offset
some of the costs by...
Enough about cost.
John Hammond entrusted me
with his dying wish,
and not once did he mention profits.
Spare no expense,
he used to say.
I appreciate that but...
the reality of operating
a theme park requires...
Don't forget why we built this place, Claire.
Jurassic World exists to remind us
how very small we are.
How new. You can't put a price on that.
Now please...
we are flying.
Breathe.
Is he ok?
Are you ok?
He is just being dramatic.
Are you still building?
We planned to open in May,
but Asset Containment insisted
we build the walls up higher.
It's bigger than expected.
It's a good sign.
We hit a few speed bumps early on.
It began to anticipate
where the food would come from.
One of the handlers nearly lost an arm.
The others threatened to quit,
if I could not guarantee their safety.
She is intelligent then?
For a dinosaur.
And that?
It tried to break the glass.
I like her spirit.
It's white.
You never told me it was white.
Think it will scare the kids?
The kids?
This will give the parents nightmares.
Is that good?
It's fantastic.
Can she see us?
They say it can sense thermal radiation.
Like snakes.
I thought there were two of them.
There was a sibling in case
this one didn't survive infancy.
Where is the sibling?
She ate it.
So,
the paddock is quite safe, then?
We have the best...
structural engineers in the world.
Yeah, so did Hammond.
There is an American Navy man here.
Part of a research program
one of my companies is running.
Owen Grady.
I know who he is.
His animals often try to escape.
They are smart.
He has to be smarter.
He only thinks he is smarter.
I want you to bring him in.
Let him inspect the paddock.
Maybe he sees something we can't.
Hold!
Hey!
Ok!
Eyes on me.
Blue?
Blue!
Watch it.
Charlie. Hey!
Don't give me that shit!
Delta!
Lock it up!
Good!
And...
we are moving!
Hold!
That's good.
That is damn good.
Very good!
See Charlie,
that's what you get!
Echo, there you go!
Delta!
Blue?
This one is for you.
Hold!
Eyes up!
Go.
You finally did it man.
Owen.
I was starting to think
I hired the wrong guys,
but damn, you got them
eating out of your palm.
You came on a good day.
It's not usually a happy ending.
Is that why you are not
sending in your reports?
We have been busy.
Not too busy to cash your paychecks.
What do you need, buddy?
A field test.
Hey.
I have just seen they can
respond to commands.
We need to take the research
and get it on its feet.
These are wild animals, Hoskins.
Trust me, you don't want them in the field.
I just saw a bond.
A real bond.
Between man and beast.
You are in my way.
Come on.
We are the same.
We are dogs of war.
We know that the military
needs to reduce casualties.
Some people think that
robots are the future.
Look, nature gave us the most effective
killing machines 75 million years ago.
And now we know they can take orders.
We finally make progress
and that's the first thing he says?
Make a weapon?
Shit.
Come on, gents.
It's grown-up time.
Drones can't search tunnels and caves.
And they are hackable.
The minute a real war breaks out,
all that fancy tech is gonna go dark.
But that tech is not gonna eat them
if they forget to feed it.
Look, look at these creatures.
They have got millions
of years of instinct in their cells,
instinct that we can program.
Their loyalty cannot be bought.
These guys are gonna run
straight into the enemy's teeth
and eat them,
belt buckle and all.
What if they decide,
they wanna be in control?
Well, then we remind them who is.
We terminate the rogues.
Promote only loyal bloodlines.
What?
What's so funny?
I don't know.
You come here
and you don't learn
anything about these animals
except what you want to know.
You made them
and now you think you own them.
We do own them.
Extinct animals have no rights.
They are not extinct anymore, Hoskins.
Exactly.
We are sitting on a goldmine.
And Masrani is using it
to stock a petting zoo.
He just wants to teach people
some humility.
He doesn't make weapons.
You think that the eighth
richest man in the world
is only into oil,
telecom,
and family fun parks?
He is so diversified,
he doesn't even know what he owns.
How long has InGen
been practicing this pitch?
Since the day
we hired you out of the Navy.
You knew the end game.
These animals,
can replace thousands
of boots on the ground.
How many lives would that save?
War is part of nature.
Look around, Owen.
Every living thing in this jungle
is trying to murder the other.
Mother Nature is way of...
testing her creations.
Refining the pecking order.
War is a struggle.
Struggle breeds greatness.
Without that,
we end up with places like this,
charge seven bucks a soda.
Do you hear yourself when you talk?
This is gonna happen.
With or without you boys.
Progress always wins, man.
Maybe progress should lose for once.
Pig loose!
Owen, no!
No, hold. No hold your fire!
Hold your fire.
Do not fire.
Put 12 amps in these animals,
they are never gonna trust me again.
Blue.
Stand down.
Hey! Hey!
What did I just say?
Delta.
I see you.
Back up!
Ok.
Good.
Charlie?
Stay right there.
Good.
Close the gate.
Are you crazy?
Ok. Just trust me.
Close the gate!
Shit.
I am ok.
You should have let them eat him.
Yeah.
You are the new guy, right?
You ever wonder
why there was a job opening?
Hey.
Don't ever turn your back to the cage.
Lift me up.
I can't see!
I am not Dad.
And you are not five.
I can still ride the Triceratops.
I am 47-and-a-half inches.
This place is for little kids.
Yeah, I know.
Wanna go on the spinning dinosaur eggs?
Nope.
Cover up your dork pouch.
Because it's my wedding.
No, Alec is not having a bachelor party.
Because all his friends are animals.
Scatter.
What?
Go. Run. Go! Go! Go!
Yuck!
Happy hour to Margarita Tour.
The next T-Rex feeding
will begin in 10 minutes.
T-Rex! Come on, man!
Please make your way for this T-Rex event.
Come on! Let's go!
Parents be aware,
this show may be disturbing
for smaller children.
Hey, Mom.
You were supposed to call me
when you landed.
Are you having fun?
Yeah.
I guess.
Aunt Claire gave us passes,
so we don't have to wait in line.
Wait, she is not with you?
Hey, Karen!
Hi, Claire. How is it going?
Yeah, everything is great.
The boys are having fun.
Everyone is...
Yeah, everyone is good.
Really?
Because I just hung up with Zach,
and he said
that you weren't even with them.
Yeah, look.
Today turned out to be
a really bad day for me.
And...
They are in great hands.
They are with my assistant.
She is British so...
they invented nannies.
Wait, are you crying?
This was supposed to be
a family weekend, Claire.
You have not seen
the boys in forever and
and I know how Zach will treat Gray
if they are by themselves.
And he can just be so mean.
Ok, I am...
I am sorry...
Tomorrow, I am gonna spend
the entire day with them.
I am going to take off work,
and I will not leave their side.
I promise.
Well, a promise tomorrow is worth
a lot less than trying today.
You are using Mom's lines now?
Oh, my God.
I am using Mom's lines.
I am sorry but you know,
I have to tell you they work.
You will see when you have kids.
Yeah if.
When...
It's worth it.
Bye, Mom.
Bye.
What do they want now?
Mr. Grady?
I need you to come...
take a look at something.
Why are you calling me Mr. Grady?
Owen.
If you are not too busy.
I am pretty busy.
We have an attraction.
That's not what you said
the last time I saw you.
I am talking about the dinosaurs,
Mr. Grady.
Owen.
A new species we have...
made.
You just went and made a new dinosaur?
Yeah, it's kind of what we do here.
The exhibit opens to the public
in three weeks.
Mr. Masrani,
wanted me to consult with you.
You wanna consult here or...
in my bungalow?
That's not funny.
A little funny.
We would like you to evaluate
the paddock for vulnerabilities.
Why me?
I guess Mr. Masrani thinks,
since you are able
to control the Raptors...
It's all about control with you.
I don't control the Raptors.
It's a relationship.
It's based on mutual respect.
That's why you and I
never had a second date.
Excuse me?
I never wanted a second date.
Who prints out an itinerary
for a night out?
I am an organized person.
What kind of a diet
doesn't allow tequila?
All of them, actually.
And what kind of a man shows
up to a date,
in board shorts?
It's Central America. It's hot.
Ok. Ok. Can we just...
focus on the asset, please?
The asset?
Look, I get it.
You are in charge out here.
You gotta make
a lot of tough decisions.
It's probably easier to pretend
these animals are just...
numbers on a spreadsheet.
But they are not.
They are alive.
I am fully aware they are alive.
You might have made them
in a test tube,
but they don't know that.
They are thinking, I gotta eat.
I gotta hunt.
I gotta...
You can relate to at least,
one of those things.
Right?
I will be in the car.
You might want to change your shirt.
They are very sensitive...
to smell.
The Mosasaurus
was thought to have hunted
near the surface of the water
where it preyed on anything
it could sink its teeth into,
including turtles,
large fish,
even smaller Mosasaurs.
Ok folks,
let's see if she is still hungry
after already eating today.
She is a little shy,
so be nice,
Zach.
And give her a hand
when she comes out.
Zach!
The Mosasaurus!
Oh, my God!
That was awesome!
Hold on tight.
We are gonna give you
an even closer look
at our Mosasaurus.
It had 88 teeth!
Wanna see something else cool?
Yeah!
We have been,
pre-booking tickets for months.
The park needs a new attraction
every few years
in order to reinvigorate
the public's interest.
Kind of like the space program.
Corporate felt genetic modification
would up the wow factor.
They are dinosaurs.
Wow enough.
Not according to our focus groups.
The Indominus Rex
makes us relevant again.
The Indominus Rex?
We needed something scary
and easy to pronounce.
You should hear a four-year-old
try to say Archaeornithomimus.
You should hear you try to say it.
So what is this thing made of?
The base genome is a T-Rex.
The rest is...
classified.
You made a new dinosaur,
but you don't even know what it is?
The lab delivers us finished assets,
and we show them to the public.
Can we drop a steer, please?
How long has the animal been in here?
All its life.
Never seen anything
outside of these walls?
We can't exactly walk it.
And you feed it with that?
Is there a problem?
Animals raised in isolation are not
always the most functional.
Your Raptors are born in captivity.
With siblings.
They learn social skills.
And I imprint on them
when they are born.
There is trust.
The only positive relationship
this animal has is with that crane.
At least she knows that means food.
So, she needs a friend.
We should schedule play-dates?
That sort of thing?
Probably not a good idea.
Where is it?
Is it in the basement?
Is there a downstairs?
Maybe it's in the rec room.
It was just here.
We were just here.
Oh, shit.
That doesn't make any sense.
These doors have not
been opened in weeks.
Were those claw marks always there?
Do you think it...
Oh, God.
She has an implant in her back.
I can track it from the control room.
We have an asset out of containment.
Put ACU on alert.
This is not a drill.
Even though I didn't meet him
until I was 13,
I definitely consider Carl to be,
more of a dad than my real dad.
Yeah.
Yeah, hello?
Lowery.
Get me coordinates on the Indominus.
Ok, yeah.
I am doing it right now.
That wall is 40 feet high.
Do you really think
she could have climbed out?
It depends.
On what?
What kind of dinosaur
they cooked up in that lab.
Wait, what the hell?
It's in the cage.
No, that's impossible.
I was just there.
Claire, I am telling you, she is in the cage.
Wait a sec...
There are people in there.
Get them out of there now.
Now!
Paddock 11, this is Control.
You need to evacuate
the containment area.
Paddock 11.
Paddock 11, do you copy?
Yeah, what is the problem?
It's in the cage!
It's in there with you!
Go!
Close the door.
We can't lock him in there with that thing.
Close it now!
Somebody talk to me!
What is happening?
Shit!
Everyone...
remain...
calm.
The implant will shock it
if it gets too close to a perimeter fence.
Ok. It's moving really fast.
This is Control.
Put out a park-wide alert.
Hang up that damn phone, please.
Sorry, I am getting new information.
Everything is fine.
Let Asset Containment capture it quietly.
The very existence of this park
is predicated on our ability
to handle incidents like this.
It was an eventuality, ok?
You should put that in the brochure.
Eventually,
one of these things will eat somebody.
That paddock is four miles
from the closest attraction.
ACU can handle this.
No one else is gonna get...
Eaten?
To all units.
This is a non-lethal operation.
Understood?
Be sweet. Calm.
Calm. Be sweet.
Be sweet.
How fast can they run?
Forty.
Fifty when they are hungry.
You ever open them up,
see what they can do?
No.
Oh, shit!
That got me.
It got me.
What do you think?
Want to take one home?
Hey, don't joke.
When I was your age,
I rescued a wolf pup.
It was, like, two months old.
It could barely walk.
It used to sleep by my bed.
Watch over me.
My wife, she came at me with a...
steak knife.
It took a chunk out of her arm.
Did you put him down?
Hell, no.
We had an...
unshakeable bond, you know?
Just like you and...
What's his name?
Delta.
And she is a girl.
Can I...
Shit.
Code 19!
That's the new one!
They said we lost two guys!
What's a Code 19?
Asset out of containment.
These people,
they never learn.
They are gonna learn all kinds of things
about their new asset now.
Hey. Yeah, it's me.
We might have an opportunity here.
You guys been here before?
If Mom and Dad get divorced,
will one of us be with Mom
and the other with Dad?
What?
Why would you say that?
Because they are.
No, they are not getting...
they are not getting divorced.
Look. You have not been around long enough.
They have always been that way.
They get mail from two different lawyers.
That doesn't mean anything.
I googled.
They are divorce lawyers.
Alright, whatever.
You know what?
It doesn't matter.
Ok? I am gonna be gone
in two years anyway.
I mean, all my friends
parents are divorced and...
Hey, knock it off.
You are gonna cry?
Look, you are gonna get
two of everything.
Right, you are gonna get two birthdays,
two Thanksgivings, two...
I don't want two of everything.
Yeah, well it's not up to you.
Alright, there is a point
you have to grow up.
I need to see a badge.
Sir, sir. I need to see a badge.
What the hell happened out there?
Sir.
There are thermal cameras
all over that paddock.
She did not just disappear!
It must have been some kind of a...
technical malfunction.
Were you not watching?
She marked up that wall as a distraction.
She wanted us to think she escaped!
Hold on.
We are talking about an animal here.
A highly intelligent animal.
400 meters to the beacon.
You are going after her with non-lethals.
We have $26 million invested in that asset.
We can't just kill it.
Those men are gonna die.
300 meters to the beacon.
You need to call this mission off right now.
They are right on top of it.
Call it off...
right now.
You are not in control here!
Blood is not clotted yet.
It's close.
What is that?
That's her tracking implant.
She clawed it out.
How would it know to do that?
She remembered where they put it in.
It can camouflage!
Evacuate the island.
We would never reopen.
You made a genetic hybrid,
raised it in captivity.
She is seeing all of this for the first time.
She does not even know what she is.
She will kill everything that moves.
Do you think the animal
is contemplating its own existence?
She is learning where
she fits in the food chain,
and I am not sure
you want her to figure that out.
Now, Asset Containment
can use live ammunition
in an emergency situation.
You have an M134 in your armory.
Put it on a chopper
and smoke this thing!
We have families here.
I am not gonna turn this place
into some kind of a war zone.
You already have.
Mr. Grady, if you are not gonna help,
there is no reason for you to be in here.
I would have a word
with your people in the lab.
That thing out there,
that's no dinosaur.
Ok.
I am going to close everything
north of the resort.
This is a Phase One, real world.
Bring everyone in.
I repeat, this is a Phase One.
Bring everyone back in.
Did you know,
the soft tissue is preserved,
because the iron in the dinosaur's blood
generates free radicals,
and those are highly reactive.
So, the proteins and the cell
membranes get all mixed up,
and act as a natural preservative.
DNA can survive for millennia that way.
See now, even if the amber mines dry up,
they will still have bones...
Shut up.
What do you think's gonna happen
from you just staring at them?
Thanks man.
You are welcome.
Enjoy the ride.
Pregnant women and those
who suffer from motion sickness
should consult with a doctor
before riding this ride.
Enjoy the ride.
Hello?
Seriously?
Sorry, folks. The ride is closed.
Everyone needs to proceed to
the monorail and exit towards the...
Come on guys, I just work here.
Due to technical difficulties,
all our exhibits are now closed.
You know that I am not at liberty
to reveal the asset's genetic makeup.
Modified animals are
known to be unpredictable.
It's killed people, Henry.
That's unfortunate.
What purpose could we have
for a dinosaur that can camouflage?
Cuttlefish genes were added
to help her withstand
an accelerated growth rate.
Cuttlefish have chromatophores
that allow the skin to change color.
It hid from thermal technology.
Really?
How is that possible?
Tree frogs can modulate
their infrared output.
We used strands from their DNA,
to adapt her to a tropical climate but...
I never imagined...
Who authorized you to do this?
You did.
Bigger.
Scarier.
Cooler. I believe is the word...
that you used in your memo.
You cannot have an animal
with exaggerated predator features
without the corresponding
behavioral traits.
What you are doing here...
What you have done.
The Board will shut down this park,
seize your work,
everything you have built.
And Hammond won't be there
to protect you this time.
All of this exists...
because of me.
If I don't innovate,
somebody else will.
You are to cease
all activities here immediately.
You are acting like we are engaged
in some kind of mad science.
But we are doing what we have done,
from the beginning.
Nothing in Jurassic World is natural.
We have always filled gaps in the
genome with the DNA of other animals.
And, if their genetic code was pure,
many of them would look quite different.
But you didn't ask for reality.
You asked for more teeth.
I never asked for a monster!
Monster is a relative term.
To a canary, a cat is a monster.
We are just used to being the cat.
Hey, there.
I am Jimmy Fallon.
Welcome aboard the Gyrosphere,
an amazing machine
made possible by science.
Your safety is our main concern.
Which is why you are behind
our invisible barrier system,
which protects you from things
like Dilophosaurus venom.
One drop of thiscan...
paralyze you, so watch out.
Is this real?
It is?
And for added protection,
each vehicle is surrounded
by aluminum oxynitride glass.
So tough,
it can stop a 50-caliber bullet.
The Gyroscopic technology
will keep you upright at all times...
Where are they?
So you have got nothing to worry about.
Oh, man.
Due to technical difficulties
all our exhibits are now closed.
Please disembark all rides,
and return to the resort.
Come on, now we can stay out
a couple more minutes.
But they said it was closed.
Aunt Claire gave us
special wristbands, right?
We are VIP, dude.
Come on.
It will be fun.
Hello?
Zara.
I need you to bring the boys
back to the hotel right away.
I don't know...
I have been looking everywhere for them.
It's just been quite a while.
Slow down.
I can't hear you.
Zach and Gray, they have run off.
They what?
Hey, Claire.
Zach, thank God.
Is Gray with you?
I can't really hear you.
We are in the hamster ball.
Ok. Zach, listen to me.
I need you to...
Hello?
Zach?
Are there any Gyrospheres
left in the Valley?
No, they are all accounted for.
It's my job.
What?
There is one in the field.
Send a team of rangers, bring them in.
Security, we need a search
and rescue in the Valley.
It's gonna be a while.
We have got our hands full out here.
No, no, no, no, no,
there are two guests missing!
You need to make this your top priority!
Just do it, man.
There is a lot of guests missing.
We are doing the best we can.
Ok. Fine. I will do it myself.
Do you think I am the one
you need to be worried about right now?
Back off!
What happened here?
Dude.
Off-road.
But they told us to go back.
I am just worried you are not getting
the full Jurassic World experience.
Claire!
I need you.
Ok.
I need your help. My nephews,
they are out in the Valley.
Please, if anything happens to them...
How old?
See...
The older one he is like...
he is high school age.
The younger one, he is...
He is...
a few years...
You don't know how old your nephews are?
No, no.
Bad idea, bad idea.
Great idea.
No!
We are gonna get arrested.
They will shave our heads,
and we are gonna have
to make root beer in the toilet.
What are you talking about?
There.
You see? I told you.
You are welcome.
Up close and personal with...
four...
dinosauruses.
Ankylosaurus.
We should not be here.
And there is five dinosaurs.
Are not you supposed to be
a genius or something?
Look.
One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
Five.
Go, go, go!
Shit!
Hold it together, man!
Drive! Drive! Go!
We are safe in here, right?
Yeah. they are totally safe.
Come on.
Pick up.
Pick up, pick up, pick up.
Zach.
I almost got it.
Zach?
Yeah?
Look.
What?
Go! Go!
Gray, go!
Oh, crap!
We are gonna have to jump.
I can't.
Are you ready?
One, two...
Come on!
You jumped.
Stay in the car.
Hi.
I know, I know.
It's alright.
Alright, girl.
Ok.
Ok. Ok. Ok.
You are ok.
It didn't eat them.
It's killing for sport.
Units on standby, ready for go.
Good. Hold off on that live feed.
We have got an evolving situation here.
Did they give you the green light yet?
They will.
Owen.
We have a situation here.
What he is doing?
Hey, there. I am Jimmy Fallon.
Welcome aboard the Gyrosphere,
an amazing machine
made possible by science.
Your safety is our main concern.
Hey, there.
Now just relax and enjoy the ride.
No, no, no.
No.
Hey.
They made it out.
Oh, my God, they jumped.
Brave kids.
Zach!
Gray!
Hey, I am not one of your damn animals.
Listen.
Those kids are still alive,
but you and I will not be...
if you continue to scream like that.
So...
You can pick up their scent, can't you?
Track their footprints?
I was with the Navy, not the Navajo.
So then what should we do?
What do you suggest we do?
You get back.
I will find them.
No, we will find them.
You will last two minutes in there.
Less, in those ridiculous shoes.
What is that supposed to mean?
It means I am ready to go.
Ok.
Let's get one thing straight.
I am in charge out here.
You do everything I say,
exactly as I say it.
Excuse me?
Just relax.
It's just like taking
a stroll through the woods.
65 million years ago.
Stay here.
You still have those matches?
Here you go.
Gray!
1992 Jeep Wrangler Sahara.
Sand Beige.
You remember when we fixed up
Grandpa's old Malibu, right?
Yeah.
Every time this thing kills,
it moves further south.
It's headed right for the park.
Why would she come here?
She can sense thermal radiation.
Our emergency measures
just put all the warm bodies in one place.
Sir...
InGen.
Hoskins.
I know who you are.
Then you know why I am here.
I have been working for two years
on an application for those Raptors.
They can hunt and kill that creature.
But your program
was to test their intelligence.
Yeah, it was.
And we did.
And in the process,
we learned something.
They follow orders.
You see, the solution to your crisis
is standing right in front of you.
Let me be as clear as I can.
No Velociraptors are going
to be set loose on this island.
Oh, shit.
You are out of your mind!
What are you going to do
with all these people?
You got 20,000 people here.
What are you going to do?
They have no place to go.
That thing is a killing machine!
And it will not stop.
Ok.
I intend to personally
look into your project,
to determine its viability,
within the moral principles
of this company.
Ok, boss.
What's your next move?
Sir, I can't get a hold of your instructor.
Never mind.
He is likely caught up in the evacuation.
You are sure there is nobody else
who can fly a helicopter?
We don't need anyone else.
You think it's out there?
I mean, I know for a fact,
it is definitely not out there,
alright?
We are totally safe.
Here,
go take this.
You are stronger than me.
Alright. Turn it over.
It works!
I thought you failed your driver's test.
No, only the driving part.
This one of theirs?
Yeah.
That road goes straight back to the park.
How did they even get
one of these things started?
Lowery, we found her.
South of the Gyrosphere Valley,
between the old park and the Aviary.
Wait, are you following the dinosaur?
Yes.
Get ACU out here.
Real guns this time.
ACU is airborne.
They took the helicopter.
Who is flying it?
Did you boys serve in the Armed Forces?
Afghanistan, sir.
Did your general ever fly
into battle with you?
Got it!
Got it.
We have eyes on the target,
south of the Aviary.
Proceed and engage.
Come on! Look alive, boys!
Look alive!
10 o'clock!
By the birdcage!
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no!
Looks like the fox got in the henhouse.
Pull up! Pull up!
Up, up, up!
We have a breach in the Aviary.
Trees, the trees!
Go! Go!
Ok, that's it.
We are safe now.
Go, go!
Go! Go! Go!
Oh, shit!
Hurry up!
Hey!
Help!
Open the gate!
Let us in!
Open it up!
Come on!
That's a first.
Open the gate!
Let us in!
Attention Aviary employees.
There has been a containment breach.
Hello?
Claire, we spotted
the boys on surveillance.
They are approaching the west gate.
I am headed there now.
Ok. Ok.
Stay right there.
I am on my way.
Stay right with them.
Hey!
Get on!
Ladies and gentlemen,
due to a containment anomaly
all guests must take
shelter immediately.
Ladies and gentlemen,
due to a containment anomaly
all guests must take shelter immediately.
Ladies and gentlemen,
due to a containment anomaly
all guests must take shelter immediately.
All units, take position on boardwalk.
Use liquid tranquilizers.
Do not fire live ammunition.
Claire, come on!
Stop running!
Wait.
Don't just stand there!
Go! Get inside now!
Zach!
Gray!
Aunt Claire!
Go, go!
Claire!
No! Hold your...
Is that Aunt Claire?
It's them!
Zach!
Gray!
Oh, my God!
Thank God! Thank God!
What happened? What is this?
Are you ok?
Where did you go?
Why didn't you come back?
I was so worried about you.
Who is that?
We work together.
Hey.
We gotta go.
Ok.
Come on, come on.
Hey, hey. You guys
can't just be walking up in...
Simon Masrani's death, was a tragedy.
The new mission,
is to prevent...
further loss of life.
Who are these guys?
I am glad you asked.
You are all relieved of duty.
There is a new team on the ground.
Lowery, I am on my way back to you.
That's a bad idea.
The board assigned emergency ops
to iNGen's private security division.
This guy Hoskins is in charge.
And he has this insane plan
to use the Raptors
to hunt the Indominus.
What do you mean use the Raptors?
Son of a bitch!
You should not say bitch.
Take the kids.
Get them someplace safe.
You got this!
Go faster!
Damn it, drive!
This does not feel safe.
Can we stay with you?
I am never leaving you
as long as you live.
No, no him.
No.
Yeah, definitely him.
Hey! Right here.
Right here.
She looks at what she wants.
Usually what she wants to eat.
The mother hen has finally arrived.
Get the hell out of here
and stay away from my animals.
Hoskins, you wanted this to happen,
you son of a bitch!
Oh, Jesus!
How many more people have to die
before this mission starts
to make sense to you?
It's not a mission.
It's a field test.
This is an iNGen situation now.
Ok, there are gonna be cruise ships
that show up here at first light.
Everybody is gonna get off this island.
You are gonna watch a news story
tomorrow?
About how you all saved lives.
No, no better yet...
how your animals saved lives.
They have never been out of containment.
It's crazy.
Let's move it out!
Let's go.
This is happening!
With or without you.
We know that she is in sector five.
This is a game we call hide-and-seek.
It's a scent drill we have done it about
a thousand times with these animals.
When they get on target...
and they will get on target.
Wait to engage.
Velociraptors are pack hunters.
They like to herd
the animal into a kill zone.
That's when we take our shot.
Get a clear shot, wait on my command,
and give her everything you got.
We got one good target, gentlemen.
Do not shoot my Raptors.
Please.
Easy, Blue.
Easy.
Attagirl.
You don't scare me.
Owen.
Are they safe?
No, they are not.
What are their names?
Well,
you got Charlie.
There is Echo.
Here is Delta.
This one is called Blue.
She is the beta.
Who is the alpha?
You are looking at him, kid.
See?
Totally safe.
Alright, get in.
Come on.
Get in there.
If you need me,
I will be right up front.
Just open that window.
Ok?
Put your seatbelts on.
Ok, so just...
Hold hands.
Nothing is getting in here, right?
Hey.
Do you remember that ghost,
at the old house?
Remember, the...
one in the garage?
I protected you, right?
You made a battle axe out of...
a ruler and a paper plate.
Yeah.
Well see, nothing is gonna get you
while I am around, ok?
But you are not
always gonna be around.
Yeah well...
Hey...
We are brothers.
Ok?
We will always be brothers and we will
always come back to one another.
No matter what.
Awesome.
Here we go.
Your boyfriend is a badass.
Imagine if we had
these puppies in Tora Bora.
Are you recording this thing?
They are slowing down.
They got something.
You know what?
No, no, no.
No, you guys are not gonna watch this.
No. no. Wait!
Keep the window closed.
Something is wrong.
They are communicating.
I know why they would not
tell us what it's made of.
Why?
That thing is part Raptor.
What's taking them so long?
Light it up!
Engage!
Oh, my God.
Watch your six.
Raptors got a new alpha.
To the vehicles now!
Fall back!
No!
No! No!
Blue!
Oh, my God.
Is everybody dead?
No, no, no.
No everyone is fine.
Don't lie to him.
He is scared.
It's ok to lie when people are scared.
I wanna go home.
Oh sweetheart, you will ok?
I promise.
Tomorrow you will be home and...
your mother will never...
let me see you again.
Get out of here! Go!
They are coming!
Just hold on back there.
Turn it on.
I don't know how.
Now!
Are you boys ok?
Hey!
Did you see that?
I can't wait to tell Mom.
Please, no.
Do not tell your mother about that, ever.
Owen!
We gotta get indoors.
Follow me.
Lowery.
We are headed your way.
Call in a chopper.
Everything must be accounted for.
I want all backup generators online.
Where have you been?
Change of plans.
Mission took a jog to the left.
I am taking everything off-site.
The embryos are safe here.
They can live up to eight
weeks on the generators.
No, no. You listen.
The park is gonna be
Chapter 11 by morning.
Ok? Our little side project
is about to get a shot in the arm.
I don't want a bunch of lawyers
messing around with something
that they don't understand.
You get it?
Hey?
I am gonna take that as a yes.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we would like to thank
you for your patience.
The next ferry
will be leaving in
45 minutes.
If you require immediate
medical attention,
please report to the nearest
health service station.
Is this what you had in mind?
Ok, people. We have an
extraction point at the east dock.
Hey.
They said we had to evacuate.
There is a boat.
You coming?
Someone has to stay behind.
Oh, no.
I have a boyfriend.
You. I didn't know...
that you guys were,
like, together, together.
We are.
Oh that's good. I just,
you don't really mention him, ever.
No, I am at work.
Oh, I know. Yeah.
Well...
Yeah.
Great.
Ok.
Are you gonna be ok?
Yeah.
Ok, bye.
Where is Hoskins?
He is sending you
and the assets to a secure location.
But our deal is still intact?
Don't worry.
You will be well taken care of.
Let's go!
Thank you for visiting Jurassic World.
We hope you enjoyed your adventure.
Don't forget to visit the gift shop,
and remember.
It's always happy hour at Margaritaville.
Those hungry.
Try the world famou...
Come on, come on.
Go inside.
Ok.
Control room.
That way.
They evacuated the lab.
What are you doing?
I am afraid that's above
your pay grade, honey.
Where is Henry?
Dr. Wu, he works for us.
That's not a real dinosaur.
No,
it ain't, kid.
But somebody is gotta make sure
that this company has a future.
Imagine,
that one,
a fraction of the size,
deadly,
intelligent,
able to hide from the most...
advanced military technology.
A living weapon unlike anything
we have ever seen.
You see...
Millions of years of evolution,
what did we learn?
Nature...
is the gift that just...
Oh, shit!
Easy.
Easy, boy.
Hey, hey.
We are on the same side, right?
Right?
Easy.
I am on your side.
No, boys.
Boys, this way. Come on.
Come on. Come on.
Come on.
That's how it is?
Easy.
That's it.
24.
50.
We need more.
More what?
Teeth.
We need more teeth.
Ok so...
you just wait here.
It's gonna be fine.
Lowery, are you still there?
Hey, where are you?
I need you to open Paddock 9.
Paddock 9?
You kidding?
Damn it Lowery be a man,
and do something
for once in your life.
Why do you have to make it personal?
Run!
Go! Go!
Doctor, come!
Oh, my God, it's your parents.
It's your parents.
Come on, come on.
Are you ok?
I am so sorry.
Come here.
Sweetie.
So, what do we do now?
Probably stick together.
For survival.
By LESAIGNEUR
Sync & corrections March 2022